<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Florence Muriuki</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Florence Muriuki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flagging Toxic Comments Part 2</title>
      <link>/post/toxic_comment_blog_part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/toxic_comment_blog_part2/</guid>
      <description>In the [previous] post, we used words to classify Wikipedia comments as harmful or harmless. In this post, we will create a few features from the comments and build another classification model.
Feature 1: Length of commentsWe would expect that harmful comments would be, on average, shorter than clean comments as clean comments would seek to offer explanations while harmful comments would dive right into attacks. Let’s take a look.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flagging Toxic Comments Part 1</title>
      <link>/post/toxic_comment_blog_part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/toxic_comment_blog_part1/</guid>
      <description>SummaryIn this post, we cover descriptions of Bayes Theorem and Naive Bayes. We thenuse Naive Bayes to classify Wikipedia comments as harmful or harmless. The model created detects 58% of harmful comments in the test data. In future posts, we improve the model by using more features and different classification models.
IntroductionMost of us find the internet entertaining and resourceful, but sometimes we come across perjoratives in various forums.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Past 10 years in headlines: Uhuru&#39;s Friends and Enemies, Corruption Web</title>
      <link>/post/kenya_newspaper_headlines_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/kenya_newspaper_headlines_blog/</guid>
      <description>In the information age, we have access to almost every piece of information imaginable in a matter of seconds. However,at any given moment, we only need very specific and negligible portions. A good example is when we are reading/watching news,we are only interested in particular segments and particular details from those segments. For some it’s sports and within the sports category, some people will pick up information only on football matches whilst others on athletes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Production in Kenya</title>
      <link>/post/food_production_in_kenya/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/food_production_in_kenya/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this project is to showcase use of R shiny in creating simple interactive dashboards. I decidedto use food production dataset because in future I would like to dig deeper into why we experience food shortagesin some parts of Kenya.
We all have our favourite foods. Some people can’t wait for their favourite fruit season andare willing to pay exorbitant amounts during the off season.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview of Kenya&#39;s Job Market</title>
      <link>/post/kenya_job_market/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/kenya_job_market/</guid>
      <description>There were 37034 jobs posted between 2016-09-07 and 2019-06-14 on jobmag Kenya. According to the chart below, 2019 has witnessed decrease in jobs posted.
Unsurprisingly, most of the top posters were recruitment agencies. Here are the recruitment and non-recruitment firms with highest number of posts:
In terms of number of jobs posted, Safaricom led the pack of non-recruitment organizations followed by Public Service Commission and Save the Children.A quick look at Safaricom posts shows that ICT/Engineering, Sales &amp;amp; Marketing, Administration, Finance/Accounting and Customer Care formed the bulk of its job posts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>